<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-09-15T20:14:57+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Robin Gandhi</title><subtitle>Director of the School of Interdisciplinary Informatics and Professor of Cybersecurity @ The University of Nebraska at Omaha</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New ADR Role!</title><link href="/news/2023/08/30/ADR.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New ADR Role!" /><published>2023-08-30T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-30T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2023/08/30/ADR</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2023/08/30/ADR.html">&lt;p&gt;Starting in Fall 2023, I am thrilled to be taking on the role of Associate Dean for Research, Technology, and Facilities at the College of IS&amp;amp;T. Our College is dedicated to fostering innovation, encouraging curiosity, and promoting research. I am eager to help our esteemed faculty lead the way in innovative breakthroughs. Our faculty and students have accomplished impressive feats by using scientific findings to develop practical solutions that benefit society. The college’s research portfolio encompasses a wide range of projects, from small-scale seed grants to large-scale interdisciplinary research centers and collaborative programs that span multiple organizations. Our intellectual contributions range from basic to applied research, and we are active in promoting student-led research and celebrating grants that support our K-12 outreach initiatives. I am committed to securing investments and planning efforts that will support and further these endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Starting in Fall 2023, I am thrilled to be taking on the role of Associate Dean for Research, Technology, and Facilities at the College of IS&amp;amp;T. Our College is dedicated to fostering innovation, encouraging curiosity, and promoting research. I am eager to help our esteemed faculty lead the way in innovative breakthroughs. Our faculty and students have accomplished impressive feats by using scientific findings to develop practical solutions that benefit society. The college’s research portfolio encompasses a wide range of projects, from small-scale seed grants to large-scale interdisciplinary research centers and collaborative programs that span multiple organizations. Our intellectual contributions range from basic to applied research, and we are active in promoting student-led research and celebrating grants that support our K-12 outreach initiatives. I am committed to securing investments and planning efforts that will support and further these endeavors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Anahuac Unviersity Visit</title><link href="/news/2022/10/07/Anahuac-University-Visit-copy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anahuac Unviersity Visit" /><published>2022-10-07T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-07T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2022/10/07/Anahuac-University-Visit%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2022/10/07/Anahuac-University-Visit-copy.html">&lt;p&gt;I had an exciting and productive visit to Anahuac University Cordoba/Orizaba campus, which is close to Veracruz, Mexico. 
I learned a lot about the culture, life, and academics at the Cordoba campus, which was very useful for me in thinking about various collaboration opportunities. My meetings with engineering students, coordinators at the Cordoba and Xalapa campuses, members of COPARMEX, and industry partners (TYASA steel plant and others) have resulted in some concrete ideas for furthering the collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Cybersecurity curricula should be available to all in an increasingly digital society. During my visit to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AnahuacCordoba?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@AnahuacCordoba&lt;/a&gt;, all career coordinators had an interest in offering this opportunity to their students. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/partnership?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#partnership&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unmc?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@unmc&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unocist?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@unocist&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AnahuacCordoba?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@AnahuacCordoba&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/OtW40M2ef3&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/OtW40M2ef3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Robin Gandhi (@robinagandhi) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/robinagandhi/status/1579548036627599360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 10, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">I had an exciting and productive visit to Anahuac University Cordoba/Orizaba campus, which is close to Veracruz, Mexico. I learned a lot about the culture, life, and academics at the Cordoba campus, which was very useful for me in thinking about various collaboration opportunities. My meetings with engineering students, coordinators at the Cordoba and Xalapa campuses, members of COPARMEX, and industry partners (TYASA steel plant and others) have resulted in some concrete ideas for furthering the collaboration.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CWE/CAPEC Board Member</title><link href="/news/2022/09/15/CWE-CAPEC-Board.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CWE/CAPEC Board Member" /><published>2022-09-15T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-15T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2022/09/15/CWE-CAPEC-Board</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2022/09/15/CWE-CAPEC-Board.html">&lt;p&gt;I am excited to be elected as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cwe.mitre.org/about/board.html&quot;&gt;CWE/CAPEC Board Member&lt;/a&gt;! It is a great group of individuals working to promote adoption while improving the coverage and quality of these knowledge bases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-the-cwecapec-board&quot;&gt;About the CWE/CAPEC Board&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The mission of the CWE/CAPEC Board is to set and promote the goals and objectives of the CWE/CAPEC Program to ensure the ongoing adoption, coverage, and quality of Common Weakness Enumeration (CWE™)/Common Attack Pattern Enumeration and Classification (CAPEC™).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Board operates according to the CWE/CAPEC Board Charter and the CWE/CAPEC Professional Code of Conduct. Members of the CWE/CAPEC Board include Technical Implementers that provide input and guidance regarding the creation, design, review, maintenance, and applications of CWE/CAPEC entries; Subject Matter Experts (SMEs) who are domain experts in weakness and/or attack pattern fields and represent a significant constituency related to, or affected by, CWE/CAPEC; and Advocates who actively support and promote CWE/CAPEC throughout the community in a highly visible and responsible manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Through open and collaborative discussions, Board members provide critical input regarding domain coverage, coverage goals, operating structure, and strategic direction. [Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cwe.mitre.org/about/board.html&quot;&gt;https://cwe.mitre.org/about/board.html&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">I am excited to be elected as a CWE/CAPEC Board Member! It is a great group of individuals working to promote adoption while improving the coverage and quality of these knowledge bases.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CAIS Paper Published</title><link href="/news/2022/01/04/journals-CAIS.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CAIS Paper Published" /><published>2022-01-04T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-04T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2022/01/04/journals-CAIS</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2022/01/04/journals-CAIS.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt; Germonprez, M., Gandhi, R. A., &amp;amp; Link, G. (2021). The Routinization of Open Source Project Engagement: The Case of Open Source Risk Management Routines. Communications of the Association for Information Systems, 49, pp-pp. https://doi.org/10.17705/1CAIS.04938&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As organizations increasingly use open source software, they inevitably routinize open source project engagement to manage new open source risks. We explore the software package data exchange (SPDX) standard as a key open source product for routinizing the work that open source risk management entails. The development and subsequent adoption of SPDX raise the questions of how organizations participate in SPDX to routinize open source work to better integrate with their own open source risk management routines, how organizations make sense of SPDX when improving their own open source risk management routines, and how a community benefits from the experiential knowledge that organizational early adopters contribute back to it. To explore these questions, we conducted a single- case, multicomponent field study in which we connected with individuals who helped to develop and later employed SPDX in their own organizations. Our results contribute to explaining how organizations routinize open source project engagement by observing organizational commitments to routinize aspects of open source risk management through communal interactions, organizationally specific interpretations, and deployments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This manuscript underwent peer review. It was received 9/17/2019 and was with the authors for eighteen months for three revisions.
Fred Niederman served as Associate Editor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Journal Germonprez, M., Gandhi, R. A., &amp;amp; Link, G. (2021). The Routinization of Open Source Project Engagement: The Case of Open Source Risk Management Routines. Communications of the Association for Information Systems, 49, pp-pp. https://doi.org/10.17705/1CAIS.04938</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Journal Papers Accepted</title><link href="/news/2021/03/29/journals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journal Papers Accepted" /><published>2021-03-29T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-29T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2021/03/29/journals</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2021/03/29/journals.html">&lt;p&gt;My Master’s student, Ovivier Avande’s thesis work was extended and developed into a Journal publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt; Avande, M. Gandhi, R., Siy, H., &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.igi-global.com/journal/international-journal-open-source-software/1123&quot;&gt;Understanding User Engagement With Multi-Representational License Comprehension Interfaces&lt;/a&gt;, IJOSSP: Volume 11, Issue 4, Article 2, Accepted, December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;License information for any non-trivial open-source software demonstrates the growing complexity of compliance management. Studies have shown that understanding open-source licenses is difficult. Prior research has not examined how developers would use interfaces displaying license text and its graphical models in studying a license. Consequently, a repeatable eye tracking-based methodology was developed to study user engagement when exploring open-source rights and obligations in multi-modal fashion. Experiences of ten participants in an exploratory case study design indicate that eye-tracking is feasible to quantitatively and qualitatively observe distinct interaction patterns in the use of license comprehension interfaces. A low correlation was observed between self-reported usability survey data and eye-tracking data. Conversely, a high correlation between eye-tracker and mouse data suggests the use of either in future studies. This paper provides a framework to conduct such studies as an alternative to surveys while offering interesting hypotheses for future studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My PhD student, Akshay Kale’s Master’s thesis work was extended and developed into a Journal publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal&lt;/strong&gt; Kale, A., Ricks, B., &amp;amp; Gandhi, R. (2021) New Measure to Understand and Compare Bridge Conditions Based on​ Inspections Time-Series Data. Journal of infrastructure systems, doi:10.1061/(ASCE)IS.1943-555X.0000633.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract-1&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The C+ score for US bridges on the 2017 infrastructure report card underscores the need for improved data-driven methods to understand bridge performance. There is a lot of interest and prior work in using inspection records to determine bridge health scores. However, aggregating, cleaning, and analyzing bridge inspection records from all states and all past years is a challenging task, limiting access and reproducibility of findings. This research introduces a new score computed using inspection records from the National Bridge Inventory (NBI) dataset. Differences between the time-series of condition ratings for a bridge and a time-series of average national condition ratings by age are used to develop a health score for that bridge. This baseline difference score complements NBI condition ratings in further understanding a bridge’s performance over time.  Moreover, the role of bridge attributes and environmental factors can be analyzed using the score. Such analysis shows that bridge material type has the highest association with the baseline difference score, followed by snowfall and maintenance. This research also makes a methodological contribution by outlining a data-driven approach for repeatable and scalable analysis of the NBI dataset.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">My Master’s student, Ovivier Avande’s thesis work was extended and developed into a Journal publication.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BBD 2020 Workshop</title><link href="/news/2020/11/01/BBD-2020.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BBD 2020 Workshop" /><published>2020-11-01T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-01T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2020/11/01/BBD-2020</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2020/11/01/BBD-2020.html">&lt;p&gt;The 5th &lt;a href=&quot;https://bridgingbigdata.github.io/pages/bbd2020.html&quot;&gt;Bridging Big Data workshop&lt;/a&gt; was a huge success! The virtual format workshop featured a great collection of talks and discussions related to  data-informed bridge infrastructure resilience in crisis times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://bridgingbigdata.github.io/pages/bbd2020agenda.html&quot;&gt;workshop agenda page&lt;/a&gt; now hosts the presentations and posters from several speakers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">The 5th Bridging Big Data workshop was a huge success! The virtual format workshop featured a great collection of talks and discussions related to data-informed bridge infrastructure resilience in crisis times.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Role: Director of Si2</title><link href="/news/2020/08/17/si2director.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Role: Director of Si2" /><published>2020-08-17T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-17T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2020/08/17/si2director</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2020/08/17/si2director.html">&lt;p&gt;I am excited to serve in my new role as the Director of the School of Interdisciplinary Informatics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The College of IS&amp;amp;T formed the School of Interdisciplinary Informatics with a strong belief that interdisciplinary education and research are necessary for preparing the next generation of IT workforce and stimulating innovation. The School is called Si2 (S-I-two) for short. As an academic unit, Si2 is home to leading interdisciplinary informatics programs in Cybersecurity, Bioinformatics, Biomedical Informatics, and IT Innovation. Each degree program draws on the in-depth foundational knowledge in life sciences, public healthcare, information security, multimedia, and the arts to build innovative curricula that transcend these fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collaborative spirit runs deep in Si2. You will find uncommon camaraderie among Si2 faculty that are passionate about “doing cool stuff.” Where else would you find a committee named COFFEE or… The COol stuFF committEE? A volunteer group of faculty from Si2 programs formed this committee to support interdisciplinary efforts and events. The collaborative spirit in Si2 is evident internally and in our academic, research, and community partnerships externally. We are proud of each degree offered in Si2 and the strategic educational partnerships with other academic units that support our students’ unique educational experience. The interdisciplinary research portfolio of our faculty is unmatched, with many nationally and internationally recognized outcomes. And we could not be more grateful to be within a thriving Omaha community that is fully engaged in ensuring our students’ success and building educational pipelines for the workforce, and providing IT opportunities for under-represented groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the leadership of our Founding Director, Dr. Ann Fruhling, Si2 saw a decade of incredible growth in our faculty numbers and student enrollments. I took on the Director’s role in Fall 2020, amid the COVID-19 pandemic. Many things have changed, and uncertainty abounds. But I am confident in our ability to continue our momentum by taking care of each other, supporting our faculty and students, and staying focused on doing what we do best — cool things! All education and research programs in the Si2 are now more relevant than ever, and tremendous opportunities lie ahead of us. I invite you to learn more about us and the outstanding education and research opportunities you will find here at Si2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unomaha.edu/college-of-information-science-and-technology/school-of-interdisciplinary-informatics/&quot;&gt;https://www.unomaha.edu/college-of-information-science-and-technology/school-of-interdisciplinary-informatics/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robin&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">I am excited to serve in my new role as the Director of the School of Interdisciplinary Informatics.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NebraskaCERT November Meeting Panelist</title><link href="/news/2019/11/01/Nebraskacert.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NebraskaCERT November Meeting Panelist" /><published>2019-11-01T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2019/11/01/Nebraskacert</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2019/11/01/Nebraskacert.html">&lt;p&gt;I will be participating in the NebraskaCERT November Meeting (November 13th at Johnny’s Cafe) as a panelist. If you in the Omaha area, I hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">I will be participating in the NebraskaCERT November Meeting (November 13th at Johnny’s Cafe) as a panelist. If you in the Omaha area, I hope to see you there!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BBD 2019 Workshop</title><link href="/news/2019/10/14/BBD-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BBD 2019 Workshop" /><published>2019-10-14T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-14T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2019/10/14/BBD-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2019/10/14/BBD-2019.html">&lt;p&gt;The 4th &lt;a href=&quot;https://bridgingbigdata.github.io/pages/bbd2019.html&quot;&gt;Bridging Big Data workshop&lt;/a&gt; was a huge success! This offering of the workshop featured a great collection of talks and discussions related to generating, analyzing and using bridge health data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://bridgingbigdata.github.io/pages/bbd2019agenda.html&quot;&gt;workshop agenda page&lt;/a&gt; now hosts the presentation and posters from several speakers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">The 4th Bridging Big Data workshop was a huge success! This offering of the workshop featured a great collection of talks and discussions related to generating, analyzing and using bridge health data.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NU Podcast</title><link href="/news/2019/09/26/podcast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NU Podcast" /><published>2019-09-26T13:56:29+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-26T13:56:29+00:00</updated><id>/news/2019/09/26/podcast</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2019/09/26/podcast.html">&lt;p&gt;The University of Nebraska today announced a new podcast series that will share stories of researchers, students and educators across NU’s four campuses who are growing the state’s workforce and quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Leading Nebraska” podcast kicks off with an &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/leading-nebraska&quot;&gt;interview with Robin Gandhi, associate professor of cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Nebraska at Omaha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gandhi discusses UNO’s leadership in addressing national challenges posed by cybercrime and training the next generation of cybersecurity experts. UNO is one of only &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsa.gov/resources/students-educators/centers-academic-excellence/cae-co-centers/&quot;&gt;21 institutions&lt;/a&gt; designated by the National Security Agency as a national Center for Academic Excellence in Cyber Operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growth in cybersecurity-related jobs well outpaces national averages, placing it among the high-growth, high-demand, high-wage fields that will be critical to Nebraska’s future economic prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s so many (cybersecurity) problems to solve and not enough people to go around,” Gandhi says in the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The biggest gratitude that I feel is when a student goes to an employer and the employer comes back and says, ‘I want more.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listeners may follow the “Leading Nebraska” podcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/leading-nebraska&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">The University of Nebraska today announced a new podcast series that will share stories of researchers, students and educators across NU’s four campuses who are growing the state’s workforce and quality of life.</summary></entry></feed>